Okay, interviews. So now
I'm going to show
you how to plan
an interview using our
template. So an interview
is basically where you
interview someone on your
channel, believe it or
not. Ideally, they have
some next level info
and your viewers are
going to love them.
So I was doing
a lot of them,
easy views, blew up
like crazy. You'll see
them all over the
place as a very
simple way of getting
views. All right, so
what are the pros
of the interview? Well,
well, easy to produce.
That's it. They can
kind of open up
partnerships. So they're good
networking. Like if you
can get a big
deal on your channel,
the value is in
the bit where you
chat to them after
the interview is finished.
They can also bring
new viewers to your
channel because if I
interviewed Casey Neistat, the
Casey fans are going
to come over and
then a small percentage
of them will probably
stick around. Cons, I
stopped making them. They
just didn't make me
any money. I was
getting like 300 ,000
views and no sales
because they don't raise
your credibility. Just a
host. So why would
anyone want to buy
your product when all
of the credibility goes
to the person you're
interviewing? So the crap
for sales and they're
very heavily reliant on
a great guest. Not
that many people make
great guests. It's hard
being interviewed. Some of
the ones I've been
on have absolutely smashed
it. Some have come
off and I'm like,
what on earth did
I just talk about?
So if you don't
have a great guest,
you ain't got a
great video. Who should
make these? Well, any
level creator can. Creators
who want to borrow
credibility from others. So
let's say you've got
a knowledge gap. So
mine in this course
right now is sales.
I just can't teach
it because I'm, although
I did sales training
years ago, I don't
feel like I'm qualified
to teach people to
do sales. So if
I wanted to talk
about that on my
channel, I would reach
out to a famous
sales person and I
would say, can you
come on? Let me
interview you about how
to do sales. So
that's kind of it.
You're filling in the
knowledge gap that you
don't have that still
serves your audience. Also,
if you're looking to
expand your next network
and kind of showcase
high trust. So let's
say I get a
really good deal. Mr.
Beast on my channel.
The fact that I
have him on my
channel, my credibility goes
up, right? Because people
are like, oh, wow,
he got this really
famous kid on the
channel. So who likes
watching these? Well, they're
very popular. People who
love behind the scenes
stories and lessons or
success paths really like
this. Also kind of
newbies topics because they're
often heavily story -based
people sharing what they
did and they're very
inspiring. So they get
information for people who
are a few steps
ahead of them. The
other kind of people
who like these are
people who are loyal
fans of the guest
and the other type
of people who just
listen. So this is
one thing I'm very
mindful of now is
that actually most people
in the education space
are not watching the
content. They're listening to
it in the background.
So this is why
they're pretty good for
YouTube because people have
them on in the
background. It gives us
that really long watch
time. So they're best
used when you have
a guest who has
a story that's really
inspirational or achieves something
cool or a framework
or result that solves
the problem your viewers
have. That's what I
would say. And if
I look at my
top performing interviews, that's
literally what they all
did. They just shared
the process and the
story that got them
a result. The secret
sauce is to pick
a guest who solves
the same problem you
do. So it's relatable
to the audience. Plan.
Everyone thinks interviews are
just something where you
just ask a ton
of questions. No, you
really need to plan
them. And we do
that in the same
way as, well, I'll
show you how to
do it in a
sec, but they are
planning
your questions. You also
want to keep in
mind when you're planning
your questions, what are
the viewers here to
learn, right? So we
don't go off on
tangents. Mistakes are when
you have like no
clear reason a guest
is relevant. When you
don't have a killer
intro that hooks people
and sets up the
credibility of your guest,
they're game over. When
you kind of let
the conversation drift and
suddenly the person's talking
about how they went
skiing and you're like,
oh, I love that
place in Switzerland too.
It's amazing. And the
viewer's sitting there going,
I didn't come for
ski Sunday. I came
here for how to
bake a cake.
I'm a huge guest
with no interesting backstory.
I know it sounds
harsh, but who cares?
And the other mistake
is thinking your big
name guests will promote
it. Nobody promotes the
interviews they go on.
It is mind blowing
because when you are
a guest on one,
these things make your
Stripe account go ping.
I've been on some
that have made me
a hell of a
lot of money. So
I always promote them.
I'm like, hit my
email list, like check
this interviewers out here,
community. I post it
on the community wall.
I make sure people
see the thing because
it's me, right? But
they don't think of
it like that. So
don't expect a big
name guest to promote
you at all. All
right. So the strategy,
your interview is all
about your intro. Watch
Dyer as CEO. They
have these insane intros
that just pump up
the curiosity and the
tension where you're like,
give me the flipping
intro. Give me the
flipping interview. Give me
the flipping interview. They're
pretty amazing. So in
your intro, you've got
to ramp up the
value a ton. You've
got to show why
they're credible, what amazing
things the viewer's going
to learn. So you
need to promise a
few things the viewer's
going to walk away
with. And then think
of interviews. You're going
to have to make
sure that you're going
to make sure that
you're going to have
a good interview. You're
going to have a
good interview. You're going
to have a good
interview. In the same
way, emotion, logic, emotion,
logic. So what you
want to do is
get your guest to
answer your questions with
a story and then
unpack the logic. If
we can do it
that way, we can
make this a much
easier watch for viewers.
Now, you can't turn
around and say, look,
you have to answer
everything with a story
because anyone who's not
media trained is going
to really struggle with
this. But that's the
name of the game
is, can we get
a really strong story
out of them? And
then get their steps
out of them so
that viewers feel inspired.
It feels new and
exciting. There's proof it
works. And then we
give them the intro.
And then you point
your end screen to
a high performing video
for sales views or
leads where you're the
expert. So I don't
think you should link
back to other interviews
because let's say this
video pops because you've
got a big guest
on. We need to
then raise your credibility.
So push into a
video where you are
the expert. So this
is our structure. Intro,
questions. But in an
ideal world, we want
this bit here to
be the most important
part of the video.
Where they talk about
how they had the
problem and how they
ended up getting the
result. And then we
can unpack the lessons
learned along the way
here or the steps
of their framework. But
most people will just
ask random questions and
stitch them together. And
that can still work.
But I think it
makes sense to pull
out the best stories.
Now, the titles for
interviews. What I would
do is I would
focus on the result
your guest has or
lessons, right? So how
the guest went from,
you know, poor to
rich. This one mistake
cost me a hundred
K and what I
learned. that's like a
quote so focus on
the lesson the result
that your viewers want
again these are just
templates you'll need to
research but don't put
an interview with steve
shule who no one's
ever heard of before
talking about something nobody
ever cares about either
like don't assume your
guests know like or
trust this person you
want to lead with
the incredible thing that
they did which is
why i covered andrew
kirby's face here because
if i put how
andrew kirby's making youtubers
money no one knows
who that is well
some people do if
you're watching this andrew
apologies i love you
um but the man
making youtubers retreat curiosity
building 200k a month
it's a big hook
wow what is it
so well casey's so
flipping famous and so
is davin goggins we
can put them but
it's very unlikely we're
going to get them
on our channel so
if you're interviewing someone
who isn't famous don't
lead with their name
thumbnails so use emotional
facial expressions from the
guest try to make
it obvious it's an
interview just think about
this right viewer expectations
if it looks like
it's going to be
an interview in the
thumbnail with the mic
and if you mike
and someone's sitting there
then that might be
helpful although i didn't
do it the title
and the way i
wrote it makes it
clear it's going to
be something like that
and then use cognitive
dissonance so basically a
thumbnail that makes people
go but i thought
that was true why
shouldn't i do that
like putting don't buy
a house results so
showing a result the
guest got or leading
heavily with curiosity so
people go how what
why the intro follows
our same framework the
hook we then set
up the problem the
guest had then the
result the guest got
and we need to
be like boom boom
boom like credibility credibility
credibility like really big
up those results they
got and then set
up what you're going
to cover in the
video so if you
would say not that
they're going to show
you how they overcame
the biggest problem their
simple framework for getting
results every time and
the one thing that's
going to see technology
picks things up it's
not that you really
have nothing if you're
gonna get to the
bottom high and Fi
habit well just having
a think and a
simple focus in that
MARK middle and FAI
but you know what
the heck is how
I'm not the best
at this and by
my the best practice
I teach physical fitness
leadership big reason nobody
ever gets results here.
And then credibility and
proof of guest as
much as possible. And
we need to make
sure we match the
viewer's expectations for the
fundamental. So here's a
snippet from one of
my intros I'll break
down, which I've color
coded here. You can
see the color code,
right? So it says,
this is Lou Levy.
She built a system
to make anyone rich
online, even if they
don't have a following.
So my hook is
basically a statement hook
saying, you can get
the thing you want
without the thing you've
been told you need.
No, really, over the
past few years, she's
helped over a thousand
regular people hit their
first ever five -figure
month online and has
generated $24 million using
it. And when I
say anyone can use
it, I mean it.
This system even made
a dog trainer $40
,000 in a month
following it. I was
so impressed with the
process, I asked if
she'd share the entire
thing with you. So
today, you're going to
learn how anyone can
come up with an
idea, create it, sell
it, and make a
ton of money online
using it. You'll also
discover why you should
buy it. And if
you're a fan of
the system, you'll also
discover why you shouldn't
sell on -demand courses
and the best way
to make money with
zero following. And then
the transitions are your
question. So it would
then cut into, all
right, Lou, so how
did you discover this
process? Or something like
that, right? So the
transitions each time are
just your questions. So
you can see here,
we've really pumped up
the credibility a ton.
She's helped a thousand
regular people, five -figure
months, generated over $24
million, even made a
dog trainer, which is
kind of unusual, $40
,000 a month. And
then the setup is
like, she's going to
show you how you
use it, and X,
Y, and Z. I
just pump up the
value. So that's how
you would write an
intro for an interview.
So let me show
you how to plan
this on our template.
So we have our
interview planner. Here's some
examples. It's very simple.
First, pick a guest.
Needs to have achieved
what your viewers want.
Ideally, they're not shy
and make sure they
actually have good insights.
Like you need to
kind of know why
they're a good guest
before you invite them
on. Set your goal.
It's very unlikely you'll
make sales from this.
I'd optimize for views
or emails, and then
focus on driving your
end screen to a
sales -based video. Complete
your thumbnails or videos.
You need to do
these before the interview.
So if I go
back to the Andrew
Kirby one, I had
a chat with Andrew
before, and we were
sitting there and I
was like, can you
just tell me what
you've been doing? So
he told me, and
I was like, wait,
so you're helping these
people make hundreds of
thousands a month for
free? He's like, yeah.
And I was like,
boom, there's our title,
The Man Making YouTubers
Rich for Free. And
then I said to
him, right, this is
our title. This is
what we're going to
build the interview around.
Just keep that in
mind when you're answering
your questions. So people
seem to think you
can't do this before,
but it actually makes
sense to build your
entire interview around your
thumbnail and title and
all the questions you
ask so that you
match and exceed those
expectations. So then complete
your thumbnail and title,
work out your viewers'
top three questions for
your setup, plan your
questions. Think about the
problems your viewers care
about. Think about asking
questions that will get
a story out of
your contestant or participant.
So for example, what
was the moment you
realized you needed to
something? And what was
the one thing that
stopped you from solving
it? They're going to
turn around and go,
ah, do you know
what? The moment I
realized was when I
was doing this, I
was doing this. The
moment I thought my
wife was going to
be my best friend
was when my wife
had just left me.
It's never going to
be a positive thing.
It's going to be
a juicy problem, which
is what we want
our story to start
with. And then you
write your intro, then
produce it. So you
can use Riverside. Riverside
is a platform that
I use where you
basically send them a
link and then you
can record it, record
in HD and then
edit the interview. I
edit the crap out
of my interviews. I've
had 45 minute interviews
down to 10 minutes.
I take out any
question where I'm like,
this isn't the best
info. Yeah, I know.
But it's always an
issue, the best info,
the best interview, the
best interview. And so,
Is this matching or
exceeding your expectations? Is
this waffle? Is this
getting in the way
of the next one,
which is a great
answer? Delete. So don't
be afraid to cut
stuff out. Diary of
a CEO, their interviews
are three hours, hour
and a half sometimes.
They cut out 50%.
It's pretty common. And
then upload and add
your tracking link. And
then you measure in
the way that I
teach you, which is
to ask, did you
hit your goal? If
so, you repeat the
lesson. If you missed
your goal, you ask
why and you avoid
the lesson next time.
Good luck.